Two worlds, one family
两个世界融为一体
Trust your heart Let fate decide
充满自信 迎接挑战
To guide these lives we see
引领我们迎向未来
A paradise untouched by man
一片蛮黄的乐土
Within this world blessed with love
这里充满了爱
A simple life They live in peace
生活朴实、自然祥和
Softly tread the sand below your feet now
轻踩着聊下的大地
Two worlds, one family
两个世界融为一体
Trust your heart Let fate decide
充满自信 迎接挑战
To guide these lives we see
引领我们迎向未来
Beneath the shelter of the trees
森林遮蔽下的世界
Only love can enter here
只有爱才能打破藩篱范例
A simple life They live in peace
生活朴实、自然祥和
Raise your head up Lift high the load
昂首冰步、拉起重担
Take strength from those that need you
让家人给你带来力量
Build high the walls Build strong the beams
筑起高墙、竖起强梁
A new life is waiting
生洗即将开展讲
But danger's no stranger here
危险却潜藏在便
No words describe a mother's tears
母亲的哀伤无法言喻
No words can heal a broken heart
破碎的心也无法闪例
A dream is gone but where there's hope
梦已破灭 但希望仍在
Somewhere, something is calling for you
它正在某处召唤着你
Two worlds, one family
两个世界融为一体
Trust your heart Let fate decide
充满自信 迎接挑战
To guide these lives we see
引领我们迎向未来
Every moment now the bond grows stronger
我们的爱从此更加坚定
Two worlds, one family
两个世界融为一体
Trust your heart Let fate decide
充满自信 迎向挑战
To guide these lives we see
引领我们迎向未来
Mama, look! Look over there!
妈妈 快看啊
- Kala! - She's back.
卡娜 地回来了…
Are you all right, dear?
你还好吧 ?
Well, isn't that...
那不是… ?
It's freaky-lookin', okay? That's what it is.
那是个怪物 错不了的
- Terkina! - Well, it is!
托托 我没说错啊
I mean, what the heck is it anyway?
它到底是什么鬼东西 ?
He's a baby.
他是个小宝宝
Well, I'm going to be his mother now.
现在开始我就是他妈妈了
You know, he's not so bad, once you get used to him.
只要看习惯了 他还襄可爱的
Kala's gonna be its mother now.
卡娜要当他的妈妈
Kerchak, I saved him from Sabor.
哥查 我从花豹不下救出他
Kala, it won't replace the one we lost.
卡娜… 他无法取代我们死去的孩子
I know that. But he needs me.
我知道 但他需要我
But it, it...
可是他…
Kala, look at it. It's not our kind.
你仔细看 他超我们不一样
No, you have to take it back.
不行 你得把他抱回去
Take him back? But he'll die.
抱回去 ? 他会死的
- If the jungle wants him... - [want him.
如果从林不要他… 我要他
I cannot let you put our family in danger.
卡娜 我不能让你危及家人
Does he look dangerous to you?
他看来很危险吗 ?
Was it alone?
只有他一个人吗 ?
Yes. Sabor killed his family.
对 他的父母被花豹咬死了
- Are you sure? - Yes.
你确定 ? 确定
There are no others.
那里没有别人
Then you may keep him.
那你可以把他留下
Kerchak, I know he'll be a good son.
他会是个好儿子的
I said he could stay.
我说他可以留下来
That doesn't make him my son.
并不代表承认他是我儿子
We will nest here for the night.
我们在这里筑窜过夜
So, what you gonna call it?
你想叫他什么 ?
I'm gonna call him...
我想叫他…泰山
.. Tarzan.
泰山?
Tarzan? Okay, he's your baby.
好吧 反正他是你的宝宝
All right, little lady, come on. It's way past your nest time.
好了 大小姐 快过来 你早该睡觉了
- Oh, Mom. - No.
妈 再等五分钟吧 ? 不行
One more minutes?
一分钟 ?
Don't cry. I'm here. Come on. Come on.
别喷 我在这里
Come, stop your crying
别再哭泣 不会有事
Just take my hand Hold it tight
紧握我的手 别放开
! will protect you from all around you
我会无微不至的保扩你
! will be here, don't you cry
我会陪伴着你 别哭泣
For one so small You seem so strong
你虽小 但却很坚强
My arms will hold you Keep you safe and warm
在我怀中 你会安全又温暖
This bond between us Can't be broken
你我的亲情坚不可摧
! will be here, don't you cry
我就在这里 别哭泣
‘Cause you'll be in my heart
因我将永远都会
Yes, you'll be in my heart
人关心你…
From this day on
从今起
Now and forever more
直到永远
You'll be in my heart
估心你
No matter what they say
不管别人怎么说
Always
直到永远
Tarzan.
泰山…
Tarzan?
泰山?
I sure scared you, Mom.
妈 我吓到你了
You sure did.
是啊
Can't you imitate any quieter animal?
你就不能学学 安静点的动物吗?
Mom, they're no fun.
妈 它们不好玩
Wanna see me be a leopard?
想看我学花豹吗?
Why don't you just come up with your own sound?
你为何不发出自己的声音呢 ?
Kala.
卡娜
Tarzan! Thank goodness you're all right!
泰山 幸好你没事
Kala and I have been so worried.
卡妞和我担心死了
Thank you. Thank you so much for finding him, Kerchak.
哥查 真谢谢你找到了他
You are such a wise and caring leader.
你是个壳智又善良的首领
Run.
快跑
- Hello! Are you thick in the head? - What?
哈鹃 你烧坏脑了吗 ? 什么 ?
How many times do I have to tell you?
我跟你说过多少次
If you want Kerchak to like you, stay away from him.
想要证哥查喜欢你 就离他远一点
Come on, Terk, step on it!
快来啊 托托
- Last one there is a dung beetle! - Yeah, the first one's gotta eat it.
最后到的是策蛋 最先到的吃大便
Terk, can l come?
我能一起去吗 ?
Well, you could if you could keep up, but, you know, you can't really keep up.
你跟得上就来吧 不过…你是跟不上的
Wait up, guys! Wait up! Right behind you!
等等我啊 等等 我马上就到
Take that! Stop hitting yourself.
别打自己…
The fun has arrived
笑星降临
- Thank you very much. - Hey, what took you so long?
多谢各位 怎么拖了这么久才来?
I had a little pest control problem, but it's all taken care of.
有个跟尾豆硬要跟来 但我把他给甩掉了
Hi, guys.
大家好
Terk, what is this, some kind of joke?
托托 这是干咏 ?开玩笑吗?
Tell me I'm not looking at the hairless wonder.
这不是那个没毛的怪物吧
Well, Terk said could come along if l could keep up.
托托说我跟得上就能来
- No, no. - Terk. Come on.
不会吧… 托托 不…
I'll handle this, guys, okay? Listen, buddy. Come here.
证我来处理 兄弟 你过来
We got a tiny, little, itsy-bitsy problem here, okay?
我们这里有个小问题
Personally, I'd love to hang out with you. You know I would.
对我来说 我很喜欢跟你玩
But the guys... they need a little convincing, you know?
但这些家伙…- 你得设法说服他们
- Okay, what do I gotta do? - Do? What do you gotta do?
好吧 我该做些什么呢 ? 做…做些什么 ?
It's so stupid.
说起来有愚蠢
What?
是什么 ?
Well, you gotta... you gotta go get a hair.
你得去…技一根毛
- Ahair? - Yeah, a hair.
一根毛? 没错,一根毛…
An elephant hair.
一根象毛
An elephant hair?
象毛 ?
Like I said, it's stupid, right?
我就说这很愚夸嘛
Listen, take it from me. Go home. Okay?
听我的话 回家去吧
Who needs this aggravation?
何必受这种气哆?
You know, I'm probably gonna leave soon myself.
我也马上就要走了
You go, I'll catch up, all right?
你先回去 我等会儿就来
You see? Leave it to me. I told you I could...
瞧 两三下就搞定 我说过…
Tarzan! Tarzan!
泰山 1泰山 别跳
That one hurt him.
那些定会疼死的
Look! There he is!
快看 ,他在那儿
- Hey, guys! - Hi.
大家好啊
This guy's great.
这小子真有趣
If he lives, you should bring him around more often.
要是他没死的话 你真应该多带他来玩
Come on, come on. Let's go get a better seat.
快…快去找个好位置吧
- It burns up the calories. - Are you sure this water's sanitary?
你确定这儿的水卫生吗 ?
It looks questionable to me.
看起来很脏号
It's fine, honey.
没问题啦 小乖
But what about bacteria?
万一有细菌怎么办?
Tantor, can't you see Mummy's talking?
丹丹 大人讲话小孩子别插踢
Watch out! There's something swimming!
小心 水里有东西在游
- It's coming right at you! - Honey, Mummy's losing her patience.
它接近你了 小冬 妈妈失去耐心中
- But this time I really see something. - Oh, boy.
但我真的有看到东西呀
Piranha! It's a piranha!
食人鱼 是食人鱼
Sweetheart, there are no piranhas in Africa.
非洲没有食人鱼
Don't tell the kid that. Of course there are piranhas in Africa.
别这么说 非洲当然有食人鱼
No, she's right. They're native to South America.
她说的没错 南美洲才有食人鱼
- Get outta here. - It's true.
少吹牛 不可能的
Think I'd be here if there were?
要是有食人鱼 我还能站在这几?
It's right behind you! Run!
它就在你后面 快跑呀
For the last time, honey, there are no piranhas in...
告诉你 小乍 根本就没有食人鱼…
My butt!
我的屁股 !
- Told you! - There's something on my butt!
我就说凡 我的屁股被咬到了
- What is it? - Are there any more of them?
有很多只吗?
- It's a piranha.
那是什么东西 ? 是一只食人鱼
Piranha!
食人鱼 !
Tantor, where are you?
丹丹 你在哪…
He's dead.
他死定了
We're dead!
我们死定了
We didn't do it! They're the ones!
不是我们 是他干的
Oh, thank you, Kerchak.
谢谢你 哥查
Tarzan, buddy! Buddy, come on!
泰山 好兄弟
Tarzan, don't die on me! Don't die on me!
求求你 千万不能死啊
- You weren't supposed to do it! - Get away!
你不该去拔象毛的 快走开啊
Don't you know a piranha can strip your flesh in seconds?
食人鱼会把你吃光的
What? He's not a piranha!
什么叫 ?他才不是食人鱼呢
You idiot!
你这个策蛋
You nearly gave me a heart attack! You happy?
你差点害我心脏病发作 这下你高兴了吧 ?
I don't believe it. You got the hair?
不可思议 你拔到象毛了?
Is that what this is all about? I got a whole tail of them.
你们想要象毛吗 ? 象毛我多得是
- Tarzan? - Terkina?
泰山…
Oh, no.
烧了
- Who's that? - My mom.
那是谁啊? 我妈
- Tarzan. - Hi.
泰山
- Hi, Aunt Kala. - Oh, you scared me!
卡娜阿姨 你吓坏我了
- What happened? - Well, I...
这是怎么一回事?
It's sort of a long... It's involved.
说来话长
Because what happened, it was a weird...
事情有点复杂…
What happened?
到底怎么一回事?
It was my fault, Kerchak.
哥查 一切都是我的错
Tarzan.
泰山?
We were playing, and... Well, I'm sorry, Kerchak.
我们只是在玩要… 对不起 哥查
You almost killed someone.
你差点就过死人了
- It was an accident. - He's only a child.
那是个意外 他还只是个孩子
That's no excuse. You can't keep defending him.
这不是借口 卡九 你不能老是太着他
- But he'll learn. - You can't learn to be one of us.
他会学乖的 他学不乖的
- You never give him a chance. - Give him a chance?
因为你根本不给他机会 给他机会 ?
Kala, look at him. He will never be one of us.
卡娜 你看看他 他永远也不会属于我们的
Kerchak!
哥查
Tarzan.
泰山…
Tarzan, what are you doing?
泰山 你在干冲 ?
Why am I so different?
我为什么长得不一样 ?
You're covered with mud, that's why.
因为你全身都是泥巴
- Kerchak said I didn't belong in... - Close your mouth.
哥查说我不属于… 不要开口
Kerchak said I don't belong in the family.
哥查说我不是一家人
Never mind what Kerchak said.
别理他说的话
- Hold still. - But look at me!
别乱动 看看我啊
lam, Tarzan.
我是在看你呀 泰山
And do you know what I see?
知道我看到什么了吗 ?
I see two eyes, like mine,
我看到两个眼睛 焉我一样
and a nose, somewhere.
还有一个鼻子 在哪里呢?
Here.
在这里
Two ears.
两个耳朵
- And let's see, what else? - Two hands?
我看看 还有什么 ? 两只手
That's right.
没错
Close your eyes.
把眼睛闭起来
Now, forget what you see.
忘记你所看到的
What do you feel?
你感觉到什么 ?
My heart.
我的心
- Your heart. - See?
你的心 看看
We're exactly the same.
我们完全一样
Kerchak just can't see that.
哥查不明和白这点
I'll make him see it.
我会让他明白的
I'll be the best ape ever.
我要当最棒的猩猩
Oh, I bet you will.
我相信你一定会的
Oh, the power to be strong
惊人的力量
And the wisdom to be wise
过人的智慧
Alf these things will come to you in time
你总有一天会扬丑旺气
On this journey that you're making
在这漫漫人生旅途上
There'll be answers that you'll seek
狗而不金地寻找答案
And it's you who'll climb the mountain
你将会克服逆境
It's you who'll reach the peak
也必将登上项峰
Son of Man, look to the sky
小泰山仰望蓝天
Lift your spirit, set it free
鼓起勇气向前冲
Someday you'll walk tall with pride
有一天你必将傲气凉然
Son of Man, aman in time you'll be
小泰山 你必将扬眉旺气
Though there's no one there to guide you
虽然没有人引导你
No one to take your hand
也没有人呵扩你
But with faith and understanding
条持信念与理解
You will journey from boy to man
你就能长大成人
Son of Man, look to the sky
小泰山仰望蓝天
Lift your spirit, set it free
鼓起勇气向前冲
Someday you'll walk tall with pride
有一天你必将傲气凉然
Son of Man, aman in time you'll be
小泰山 你必将扬眉旺气
In learning you will teach
在学习中成长
And in teaching you will learn
在成长中学习
You'll find your place beside the ones you love
你将会找到冯属
Oh, and all the things you dreamed of
你所梦想的一切
The visions that you saw
你所向往的美景
Well, the time is drawing near now
已不再区不可及
It's yours to claim it all
时机已经到来
Son of Man, look to the sky
小泰山仰望蓝天
Lift your spirit, set it free
鼓起勇气向前冲
Someday you'll walk tall with pride
有一天你必将傲气凉然
Son of Man, aman in time you'll be
小泰山 你必将扬眉旺气
Son of Man
小泰山
Son of Man's a man for all to see
你必将扬眉吐气
Don't even think about it.
你吓不到我的
- How'd you know it was me? - I'm your mother. I know everything.
你怎么知道是我 ? 我是你妈 我什么都知道
- Where have you been? - [thought you knew everything.
你跑到哪儿去了? 你不是什么都知道吗 ?
Hey, Auntie K, you're looking remarkably groomed today.
卡娜阿姨 你今天好漂亮啊
Hello, Terk.
托托 你好
Not the neck! Not the neck there, T.
别择到我的脖子…
Okay, it's all fun and games till someone loses an eye.
要是有人青断手聊就不好玩了
- And it's always me. - Cramp. Cramp in the calf.
我的小爵抽季了
- Please! - Okay. Okay, you win.
好啦 你赢了
Okay, okay, you win. Hello! Down here. Yo, yo! Let go!
好了 算你赢了… 快放开我啊
- Oh, sorry, Terk. - What kind of animal are you?
对不起 托托 到底是什么鬼动物啊?
You know, I been thinking lately that maybe Tarzan
我在想泰山可能跟大象
could be some subspecies of elephant.
有血源父系
What are you, crazy? An elephant?
你鸳了吗 大象?
Listen to me. Think about it. He enjoys a peanut, I enjoy a peanut.
听我说 你想想看… 他喜欢花生 我也喜欢花生
He looks nothing like you.
他跟你长得一点也不像
Okay everybody, move aside. Outta my way.
大家靠边站 快让开
Best friend coming through. That would be me.
好朋友来了 那就是我
And you, don't make a habit of that, okay?
你啊 可别养成那样的坏习惯
There are other ways of getting attention.
想引人注意有很多种方法
- I'll try to remember that. - All right.
我会记住的 那就好
Il was right behind you if you needed me. I had you covered.
如果需要帮手 我随时…
What was that?
那是什么 ?
It wasn't me, I swear.
我发拟 不是我干的
Okay, well, maybe it was.
好吧 也许吧
Everyone, let's move.
大家听着 我们快走吧
l was reminded of a safari Il led up the Zambezi.
这证我想起 在尚比加打猎的那光经验
Marvelous. Lots of hunting, yes. Bang, bang, bang, bang, bang.
哎哟 太精彩啦 什么都可以打
Wildebeest everywhere.
到处是野蜜蜂
Two bearers loading three rifles for me, blasting away.
有两个人 才我装三把枪的 子弹 我就这样束他们
That's when I knew l was born for Africa
所以我生来就属于非洲
and Africa was created for...
非洲也是因我…
Clayton?
克里顿 ?
Clayton... Oh, there you are.
克里顿 原来你在这里
What is it? What is it, Clayton? Are we in danger?
怎么了? 怎么了?有危险吗?
I thought I saw something.
我好像看到什么了
Is it a Hippopotamus amphibious or a Rhinoceros bihornus?
是河马吗?还是只犀牛?
- Professor, don't move! - Oh, right.
教授 别动 好
Daddy?
邓
Daddy, what's all the hullabaloo about?
各 为什么这么吵啊?
What is it, Daddy?
怎么一回事 和葡?
Mr. Clayton asked me not to move. He saw something.
克里顿叫我别动 他似乎看到了什么
l moved.
我动了
Uh, Mr. Clayton? Sorry, excuse me.
克里顿先生 对不起
But my father and I came on this expedition to study gorillas,
我和父亲是来研究大猩猩的
and I believe your shooting might be scaring them off.
你的枪声可能会把它们吓走
You hired me to protect you, Miss Porter,
是你雇请我来保扩你们的
and protect you I shall.
因此我必须尽责地保护你们
And you're doing a marvelous job of it.
你做得很好
But we only have a short time before the ship returns, you see...
不过我们的船很快就回来了
Jane! Jane, do you realize what you're standing in?
珍妮 你知道你正站在 什么东西上面吗?
- Agorilla's nest! - Daddy!
大猩猩的宽 邓
At last! Our first sign in days.
费了几天功夫 终于找到了
Do you think the beasts could be nearby?
你想它们会在附近吗 ?
Could be. Why, I mean, there's the evidence.
有可能…- 证据就在这里了
They can't be very far, anyway.
它们不会离太远的
Look! Over there and there...
和爸 你看那些
Where? Yes, more nests!
什么 ? 还有更多的帘
- l see them! - Just as you predicted!
我看到了 跟你说的一样
Family groups!
一个家族
Oh, Jane, I love you.
珍妮 我爱你
Family groups?
家族 ?
Excuse me, but these are wild beasts
小尾 它们是弛猛的野兽
that would sooner tear your head off than look at you.
一张口就能咬掉你的头
On the contrary, Mr. Clayton.
正好相友 克里顿先生
Daddy's theory is that these are social creatures, not monsters.
依照和爸和爸的理论 它们是温驯的…
Mr. Clayton, please. What if it's a gorilla?
克里顿先生 求求你 万一那是大猩猩怎么办 ?
It's no gorilla.
那不是大猩猩
- Perhaps we should press on. - Yes, indeed.
也许我们该继续走 当然
Now, we should keep heading west, following the Ganoderma ablonatum.
我们应该跟着某究往西走
Excellent, professor.
好极了 教授
I could've used your expertise on my last safari.
我可以仰赖你的专业知识
Are you what all the fuss was about?
原来是你这小家伙若的福
Daddy! Daddy, quick!
和爸…- 和爸 快点来
No, wait. Hold still.
等等 别乱动
Oh, my good...
我的天啊…
There you go. What do you think?
你看 觉得怎样 ?
Why, you little...
你这个小淘气
Well, this is absolutely peachy.
这真是太棒了
Come to study gorillas and get my sketchbook pinched by a baboon.
来这里研究猩猩 素描薄却被狂狂拿走了
Give me that!
还给我
Come on now, enough of this. l want this paper on the count of three.
好了 闹够了吧? 数到三就把画还给我
One.
-一
Two.
人
Look, bananas!
快看 有香攻
I can't believe you fell for that one.
真不敢相信你居然会被我骗了
No, no, don't give me those crocodile tears.
少来了 别对我来这套
What would your parents have to say?
你和苞妈会怎么说?
You see, I told you they'd be cross.
看看吧 我就说它们一定会很生气
Go easy on him. Children will be children.
别打它 它还是个小孩咏
I'm flying!
我在飞
What on earth am I...
怎么会?
Get off! Get off!
放开、快放开
Put me down! Put me down!
放下 快把我放下
Help!
救命啊 !
Unhand me, monkey!
放开我
Over there!
小心那边
I'm in a tree with a man who talks to monkeys.
我跟一个会说猴语的人 一起在树上
I can't do this. I can't...
我不敢下去 不行
This is good. This is very good.
这下可好 真是太好了
Wait.
等等
One, two.
-一    -
It can't get any worse, can it?
不会更惨吧
Obviously it can.
看来是会的
Stay back. No, don't... Don't come any closer.
退后 不 别过来 求求你
What are you... What are you doing?
你要干什么 ?
No, please don't. That tickles.
别这样 好痒吕
No, get off, get off. Get off!
放开…放开
It serves you right.
你活该
Stay away from me, like a very good wild man.
乖嗓人 你离我远点几
You stay. I'm warning you.
别过来 我警告你
My father won't take kindly to you...
我爸可不会轻贷你的
No. That's... That's close enough.
不要 这样够近了
How dare you?
你真大胆
Oh, dear.
天啊…天啊…
Yes, thank you.
谢谢你
That's a lovely heartbeat. It's very nice.
心跳很好听
- It's very nice. - Oh, thank you.
谢谢
I can't do a thing with it in this humidity though.
十下得这么大我也没办法
You do speak!
你会讲话嘛
All this time I thought you were a big, wild, quiet, silent person thing.
我一直以为你是个沉鞭的野人
Why didn't you tell me? I must say I'm rather curious as to who you are.
你怎么不早说呢 ? 我很好奇你是谁 我想…
Tarzan.
泰山
Oh, I see.
我懂了
I'm Jane.
我是珍妮
Jane. Tarzan.
珍妮 泰山
Jane.
珍妮
Exactly.
没错
Clayton!
克里上顿
- Clayton. - Extraordinary.
真不可思议
Please, can you take me to my camp?
求你啦 可以带我回我的营地吗 ?
Yes, Clayton. Wonderful.
对 克里顿 很好
Can't we walk?
我们可不可以走回去呢 ?
- Let's hope we find him before Kerchak. - Maybe he's lost.
希望我们比哥查旱一步找到他
- Or found something more interesting. - Are you nuts?
也许他找到更有趣的朋友了
Hey, what's everybody looking at?
你们在看什么 ?
The horror!
好届怖
It's gruesome. Hide me!
好可怕 快生起来
Pull yourself together. You're embarrassing me.
人镇静点 你真是去脸
These things aren't alive.
这些东西是死的
I knew that.
我时知道了
What kind of primitive beasts are responsible for this mess?
什么样的野普 会摘出这一团错哆?
Come here, you guys! Come here, come here!
过来 你们快来看啊
- Look at this. - What is that thing?
这是什么 ?
Do it again, do it again.
再来一灾…
Like this?
这样吗 ? 好叹
Rip it!
撕吧
Ding! I love that part.
叮…我就喜欢这声音
Let me hear it, big fella.
你来打吧 大个子
Now, hit it!
开始吧
Nice.
很好
What the heck? Bye-bye.
什么鬼东西 ? 一边去
Yeah, Tant.
好哎 丹丹
Now, hit it.
一起来
Come on, Tantor.
快吹啊 丹腊
I love it.
我喜欢
Stay with me, fellas.
大家跟上节奏
I feel something happening here.
我觉得插有趣的
Gorillas!
大猩猩
He's one of them.
他也是其中之一员
Oh, my...
我的天啊
Jane, where are you?
珍妮… 珍妮 你在哪里?
Are you all right? We've been everywhere.
你还好吧 ? 我们一直在到处找你
Oh, my goodness.
天啊
Daddy, I was out walking...
和爸 我本来在走路
- Yes, yes. - Little baby. Little baby monkey.
后来我蔡一只小猴子
- [ drew a picture. - Go on.
西 醴
- The monkey starts crying. - Poor baby.
继续说
But I turned round, and there's a whole fleet of them!
我一转头就看到一大群猴子
- A huge tree full of them... - Monkeys?
整棵树上到处都是猴子
..screaming at me!
对着我大叫
Theropithecus baboonus. She's very good at this.
那是狂狂 她学得很像
- Really? - Terrified, I was.
是吗? 我吓坏了
Suddenly, I was swinging in the vines, up in the air!
突然间 我就在树蕨中摆荡
- With the monkeys? - Flying.
吐猴子一起? 摆荡、飞行 像个空中飞人
- In the air. - And I'm all surrounded.
空中飞人 我被团团围住了
- What did you do? - And, Daddy, they took my boot!
然后呢 ? 然后它们抢走了我的靴子
- Those are the ones I bought you. - And l was saved!
那双是我买给你的 后来我得救了
Il was saved by a flying wild man in a loincloth.
被一个身穿缠腰布的飞行野人 救了起来
- Loincloth, good Lord. - What is she talking about?
缠腰布 ? 天啊 她在讲什么啊?
l haven't the foggiest idea. Takes after her mother, you know.
我根本搞不清楚 她这点真像她妈妈
She'd come up with stories. Not about men in loincloths...
她也会编故事 当然不会说什么缠腰布…
- And there were gorillas! - Gorillas?
后来大猩猩来了 大猩猩?
- They were doing... - You saw the gorillas? Where, Jane?
你看到大猩猩了?在哪里?
- He left with them. - Who, dear, who?
他趴它们一起走了 谁呀?是谁?
Tarzan.
泰山
Tarzan?
泰山?
The ape man.
人猿泰山
Everyone. We will avoid the strangers.
大家听好 诅开陌生人
Do not let them see you, and do not seek them out.
别被他们看到 也别去找他们
They mean us no harm, Kerchak.
他们并没有恶意
- [don't know them. - ldo. I've spent time with them.
泰山 我不认识他们 我认识 我跟他们相处过
You may be willing to risk our safety, but I'm not.
就算你能 我也不能 危及大家的安全
Why are you threatened by anyone different from you?
你为什么老是害怕异类 ?
Protect this family, and stay away from them.
保扩家人 离他们远一点
Tarzan, for once, listen to Kerchak.
泰山 这次就听哥查的话吧
Why didn't you tell me there were creatures that look like me?
你为什么不告诉我 有人跟我一样 ?
Well, he didn't stand upright. He sort of...
他不会直立
- ...crouched. - Really?
像是在蹲站 真的?
He supported his weight on his knuckles.
他只用手指侨节支撑重量
- On the knuckles. - See? Exactly like a gorilla.
用他的手指估节 就跟大猩猩一样
- Extraordinary. - It was amazing!
太奇特了 真是不可思议
He'd bend his elbows out like this. And then he walks, like this.
他会变起手肘像这样走路
Oh, I see! Like Aunt Isabel.
就像伊莎贝阿姨
This is capital!
这真是太棒了
Janey-Jane, what a discovery!
珍妮 这是个惊人的发现
A man with no language, no human behavior...
不会人类语言和行为的野人
And no respect for personal boundaries.
也完全不懂得尊重别人
- How do you mean? - He was this close, Daddy.
什么意思 ? 他靠得这么近
Staring at me.
直直地枉着我
He seemed confused at first,
一开始有点迷感
as if he's never seen another human before.
好像从没看过人类似的
And his eyes were intense and focused, and...
他的眼神强烈专注
I've never seen such eyes.
我从没看过这种眼神
Shall l leave you and the blackboard alone for a moment?
是不是让你 四黑板先独处一下呢?
Daddy, stop it.
和爸 别冰了
The point is, think of what we could learn from him. We must find him.
重点是 我们可以从他身上 学到很多东西
Professor, you are here to find gorillas,
教授 你是来找大猩猩的
not indulge some girlish fantasy.
而不是来追寻小女孩的幻想
Fantasy? I didn’t imagine him.
幻想?那才不是我的幻想呢
Tarzan is...
泰山是…
- Professor, Jane, stand back! - Wait!
教授、珍妮 快退后 等等 不
Clayton.
克里上顿
Have we met?
我们见过吗 ?
How does he know my name?
他怎么会知道我的名字 ?
He thinks it means the sound of a gunshot.
他以为那是代表枪声
l see what you mean about those personal boundaries.
他真的是不太尊重别人
What's he doing?
他在做什么 ?
Look at him, Jane.
看看他 珍刀
Moves like an ape, but looks like a man.
举止像猩猩 长相却像人类
He could be the missing link.
他可能会是人类进化的估键
Or our link to the gorillas.
或是帮我们找到大猩猩的向导
Yes, yes.
没错
Where are the gorillas?
大猩猩在哪里?
Go-ri-llas!
大猩猩
Shouting won't help, Mr. Clayton. He doesn't understand English.
对他大吼大叫是不会有用的 他不懂英文
Then I'll make him understand.
我会让他懂的
If lcan teach a parrot to sing God Save the Queen,
既然我能 教鹦葡喝「上帝保佑女王1
I can certainly teach this savage a thing or two.
也就绝对能教 这个野人听懂两句话
Gorilla.
大猩猩
- He's got it! - Gorilla.
他学会了
Perhaps not.
也许没学会 不对…不对…
Gimme that. Leave it.
给我 别冰了
Mr. Clayton, I think I'll take it from here.
克里顿先生 还是让我来吧
Whatever you do, I'll do it too
不论你做什么 我也跟着做
Show me everything and tell me how
让我知道一切 告诉我原由
It all means something
这一切对我既陌生
And yet nothing to me
又熟荡
! can see there's so much to learn
有那么多事等待着我去学习
It's all so close and yet so far
这一切对我既吐远又接近
l see myself as people see me
我终于了解我和他们都一样
Oh, I just know there's something bigger out there
我知道外面有个大千世界
! wanna know, can you show me
我想知道一切 请教教我
! wanna know about these strangers like me
我想认识这些黑我一样的人
Tell me more, please show me
告诉我多一些 请教教我
Every gesture, every move that she makes
她的样子、她的动作
Makes me feel like never before
都让我有种不一样的感觉
Why do I have this growing need to be beside her
我有种想陪伴着她的感觉
These emotions I never knew
这些感觉好陌生
Of some other world far beyond this place
外面就是花花世界
Beyond the trees, above the clouds
就在从林之后、云彩之上
! see before me a new horizon
我看到一处困新的天地
! wanna know, can you show me
我想知道一切 请教教我
! wanna know about these strangers like me
我想认识这些黑我一样的人
Tell me more, please show me
告诉我多一些 请教教我
Come with me now to see my world
跟随我看看我的世界吧
Where there's beauty beyond your dreams
这里有前所未有的美景
Can you feel the things I feel
你是否也有跟我一样的感党 ?
Right now, with you
带领我
Take my hand
我要了解
There's a world I need to know
这个世界
We've wasted all this time on what he wants.
我们为他浪费太多时间了
The boat could arrive any day. Now, ask him straight out.
船随时会到 快去问他吧
Tarzan, will you take us to the gorillas?
泰山… 你可以带我们去找大猩猩吗 ?
Do you understand?
你懂吗 ?
l understand.
我懂
- Good work, Jane. - Well?
很好 珍妮 怎么样 ?
- lL can't. - What?
不行
- Why not, Tarzan? - Kerchak.
为什么不行? 哥查
! wanna know, can you show me
我想知道一切 请教教我
! wanna know about these strangers like me
我想认识这些黑我一样的人
Tell me more, please show me
告诉我多一些 请教教我
! wanna know
我想知道
Oh, Terk, I've never seen him so happy.
托托 我从没见他这么快乐过
Yeah? I give it a week.
我看最多就一星期
- Aye, cut her loose! - Come on, pull it down.
破断绳子
- All right, move it, ya bilge rats! - Heave ho, lads.
动作快点…
I've waited 30 years for this and I won't leave until l see a gorilla.
我等了三十年 看不到大猩猩我不会走的
Isn't this dreadful, Tarzan? No! No, no, wait!
真糟糙啊 泰山 等等…
You're the captain.
你是船长啊
Tell them you've had engine trouble, and give us two more days.
就说引擎故障 再多等两天
And be late at every port from here to London?
这样会耽误所有的行程
We'll have come for nothing.
我们大老远跑来一无所获
I'm sorry, Miss Porter, but I simply can't do it.
布小姐 很抱娄 想难从命
This is your fault.
都是你的错
I should've followed my instincts and set traps for the beasts.
我应该赁直觉设陷阱捕捉的
Don't you think I'm disappointed about the gorillas?
我也很失望啊 你真是不可理喻
The boat's arrived.
船来了
The boat that's come to take us home, to England.
这艇大船要载我们回伦敦
Well, we really hope that you'll come with us.
我们希望你能一起来
Won't you?
好吗 ?
Go see England today. Come home tomorrow.
今天去英国 明天就回家
Not come back?
回不来 ?
I know it sounds awful, but you belong with us, with people.
我知道这有点糟耕 但你属于我们 你是人类啊
Jane must stay with Tarzan.
珍妮际泰山一起留下来
Stay here?
留在这儿?
No, I can't stay. Look, I've got...
我不能留下来
I'm with my father, and...
我得跟笃和区走
Jane... stay.
珍妮 留下来
- But... - Please.
求求你
But, I can't.
但…我办不到
Women.
女人都是这样的 谢谢你
Even if you hadn't grown up a savage, you'd be lost.
就算你不是野人也一样
There are no trails through a woman's heart.
女人心海底针啊
- Jane is going. - Yes.
珍妮要走了 是啊
If only she could've spent more time with the gorillas.
她只希望能多花点时间 去找大猩猩
She's so disappointed.
她好失望 难过到极点了
Sorry, old boy.
很遗憾 小子
Oh, well, l best get Jane's things to the ship.
好吧 我最好赶快把她的东西 据上船去
Clayton.
克里上顿
If Jane sees gorillas, she stays?
珍妮看到大猩猩 就会留下来吗 ?
Say, that's why she came, isn't it?
这就是她来的原因 不是吗?
- I'll do it. - Good man!
我带你去 好小子
- Snipes? - Sir?
史罕普
Get the boys together. There's gonna be a change in plans.
集合大家 计划有变
Terk, just get Kerchak out of the way.
托托 你只要把哥查引开就好
- What? - I'd be happy to get...
什么 ?
Hey! Shut your trunk and get me out of here.
闭上你的象踢 快带我走吧
Can you believe that guy?
你相信吗?
Drops us like a newborn giraffe, kerplop!
这家伙就这样思掉我们
Now waltzes in here and expects us to just...
现在突然出现竟然要我们…
Terk, I'm asking you as a friend.
托托 我是以朋友的身分请求你啦
With the face and the eyes and the...
别用那种眼神看着我
All right! But don't make me do anything embarrassing.
好吧 不过可别让我做什么训事
I'm gonna kill him!!
我要宰了他
I thought that dress was rather slimming on you.
我觉得你穿这条裙子插淋亮的
Really? I thought it was a little revealing and kind of...
是吗? 我倒觉得太暴露了…
How does she move in this thing?
她穿着这玩意要怎么走路啊 ?
- Look, Daddy! - Where?
和爸 快看 哪里 ?
Now, be careful, professor.
小声点 教授
Mustn't, mustn't frighten.
别把它吓跑了
She's beautiful.
它好漂亮啊
She's my mother.
她是我母亲
This is your...
这是你的…
..mother?
母亲 ?
- What's happening? - [don't know, Daddy.
怎么回事? 我不知道
- It's getting away! - No! You'll only frighten her more.
它躲开了 不 你这样会吓跑它的
Yes, absolutely, my dear. Good idea.
很好 很棒的点子
What are you doing? Want to frighten them?
你们在干什么 ?
Get up. Get...
起来
Don't get up.
千万别起来
Hello.
你好
It's very nice to meet you, too.
我也很高兴认识你
Oh, Your Majesty, you're such a tease.
女王陵下 你真爱开玩笑
Archimedes Q. Porter at your service.
布教授愿为您效劳
Quite a grip you've got.
你的力气真大啊
Thank you, yes. Is that one of mine?
谢谢 那是我的吗 ?
This is wonderful, Mr. Clayton!
太好了 克里上顿
Look, look! Social grooming.
快看 它在帮我梳理毛发呢
Congratulations, professor.
茶喜了 教授
Our dream has come true.
我们的梦想成真了
Give me that!
还给我
Hold on now. Leave that!
别乱来
That is not to be played with!
那可不是玩具啊
Can you teach me?
你能教我吗 ?
- Speak gorilla? - Yes.
说猩猩话 ? 是啊
That Jane stays with Tarzan.
珍妮际泰山一起留下来
Stay? But I, l thought we'd already...
留下来 ? 但我说过…
Tarzan, l...
泰山 我…
- ls that my dress? - Oh, no.
那是我的裙子吗 ? 烧了
Daddy.
和爸和爸
Give it to me!
还给我
Go!
不
Wait, wait! Tarzan!
等等 泰山
Go now!
快走吧
Jane, quickly! Hurry! Come along!
珍妮 我们快点走吧
Kerchak, I didn't...
哥查 我不是故意…
- I'm sorry, lL... - lasked you to protect our family.
我叫你保扩家人
And you betrayed us all.
而你却背叛我们
I'm so confused.
我好困 感
Come with me.
跟我来吧
There's something I should've shown you long ago.
有些东西我早该带你去看了
Is this me?
这是我吗?
and...
还有我的…
Now you know.
现在你知道了
Tarzan, I just want you to be happy,
泰山 不管你的决定如何
whatever you decide.
我只希望你快乐
No matter where I go, you will always be my mother.
不管我去到哪里 你永远都是我的母亲
And you will always be in my heart.
我也会永远居记着你的
Goodbye, Tarzan.
再见了 泰山
We're too late! I can't believe it!
太迟了 真不敢相信
If you had pulled over and asked for directions...
要是你背问路就好了
We didn't get to say goodbye.
我们还没来得及说再见
Well, good riddance, all right? Who needs you, huh?
那也好 谁需要你呀
Go on, get out of here, bald boy!
快滚吧 无毛小子
You, you ingrate! You bald ingrate!
忘恩负义的家伙
Go on and rot, for all 1 care!
我才不在卑你呢
Go!
滚吧
What are you looking at?
你看什么看 ?
I'm gonna miss him, too.
我也会想念他的
Tarzan, you can't imagine what's in store for you.
泰山 你一定会大开眼界的
You'll see the world.
你可以看看这个世界
Everyone's going to want to meet you. Kings, scientists, famous writers.
所有的人也会抢着来看你 国王、科学家、知名作家
Yes. Darwin and Kipling. Queen Victoria!
达尔文、吉下林、英国女王
l haven't met her, but I heard she's nice.
我没见过她 听说她的人很好
And I'll be with Jane?
我能跟珍妮在一起
Yes, with Jane.
是啊 当然了
Slippery.
好滑
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事?
Clayton! Clayton, help!
克里顿 快帮帮忙
Have we met?
我认识你吗 ?
Yes, the ape man.
对了 你是那个人猿
Clayton, you...
克里顿 你…
You...
你…
So sorry about the rude welcome, old boy,
抱娄对你动粗了
but I couldn't have you making a scene
但我可不能证你车是生非
when we put your furry friends in their cages.
我要把你的长毛朋友人起来
Why?
为什么 ?
For three hundred pounds sterling a head.
每头猩猩值三百英镑呢
Actually, l have you to thank, my boy.
对了 我还得谢谢你呢
Couldn't have done it without you.
没有你 我可办不到啊
Lock him up with the others.
把他跟其他人一起估起来
That sounded like Tarzan.
听起来像是泰山
He sounded like he was in trouble.
他好像有麻烦了
Well, why doesn't he get his new friends to help him? I don't care.
让他去叫他的新朋友帮忙吧 我才不管呢
That's it!
够了
I've had it with you and your emotional constipation!
我受够你这个醋坛子了
Tarzan needs us and we're gonna help him!
泰山有难 我们得去救他
You got that? Now, pipe down and hang on tight!
你懂了吗 ? 给我闭嘴 抓紧了
We've got a boat to catch.
我们要赶去搭船了
I've never felt so alive!
我从未这么有活力过
Good! 'Cause I'm gonna kill you!
很好 那我就让你活不下去
No time for that now, missy.
别浪费时间了 小姐
Tarzan, it's no use. Don't!
泰山 没有用的 别这样
- Clayton. - Yes, Clayton.
克里上顿 没错 是克里顿
Clayton betrayed us all. I'm so sorry, Tarzan.
他出卖了我们 对不起 泰山
No, I did this.
不 是我的错
I betrayed my family. Kerchak was right.
是我背叛了家人 哥查说得对
Those magnificent creatures, shivering in cages.
那些大猩猩 不该被人关进笼子里的
What is this world coming to?
这是什么世界啊
Oh, by Jove! Don't know my own strength.
老天 我的力气真大啊
What was that?
那是什么 ?
You are an animal!
你还真是野变啊
That sounded just like an elephant.
听起来像是只大象
Tantor!
丹有丹
Thanks, guys.
谢了 朋友
I thought I would never see you again!
我以为我再也看不到你了
Sometimes you embarrass me.
你有时真让我没面子
l remember you.
我记得你
I think this one will be better off stuffed.
我想这只最好是做成标本
You came back.
你回来了
l came home.
我回家了
Fire!
发射
You there! Take what you can back to the boat.
你们快把猩猩抬上船
I've got some hunting to do.
我还要打猎呢
Don't worry.
别担心
I'm going to have you out of this in a second.
我马上救你出来
This should do the trick.
这应该会有用
Hiding, are we?
想躲?
- Good! - Clayton, you...
很好 克里顿 你…
I could use a challenge. Because after I get rid of you,
我喜欢挑战 等我除掉你
rounding up your little ape family will be all too easy!
抓你的家人就太容易了
Be a man.
像个男子汉
Not a man like you!
我不想跟你一样
Clayton, don't!
克里顿 住手
Kerchak, forgive me.
哥查 原谅我
No, forgive me for not understanding
不 原谅我不能理解
that you have always been one of us.
你一直都是我们的家人
Our family will look to you now.
现在你是一家之主了
No, Kerchak.
不 哥查
Take care of them...
好好照顾他们
..my son.
儿子
Take care of them.
照顾他们
London will seem so small compared to all this.
伦敦跟这里比起来好渺小吕
I will miss you, Jane.
珍妮 我会想念你的
- Miss Porter! - know. I'm coming.
布小姐 我知道 我来了
Well... l suppose we should say goodbye.
我想我们该说再见了
Goodbye.
再见
Goodbye, Tarzan!
再见了 泰山
I'm going to miss that boy.
我会想念这孩子的
Jane, dear, I can't help feeling that you should stay.
珍妮 我觉得你该留下来
Please don't. We've been through all of this.
和爸 别说了 我们谈过了
I couldn't possibly...
我不能留下来
belong in England with you, with people...
我的家在英国 跟你在一起 还有人和群
But you love him.
可是你爱他
Go on.
去吧
Thank you. Thanks for getting my glove.
谢谢 谢谢你帮我捡手套
What am I doing?
我在干什么 ?
Captain, tell them that you never found us, eh?
船长 就说你没找到我们吧
After all, people get lost in the jungle every day.
每天都有人在森林里失踪的
Tootle-pip.
再见了
Put your faith in what you most believe in
对自己的信念坚定不移
Two worlds, one family
两个世界融为一体
Trust your heart, let fate decide
充满自信 迎接挑战
To guide these lives
引领我们迎向未来
To guide these lives we see
对自己的信念坚定不移
Two worlds, one family
两个世界融为一体